export const chapter = "Chapter - 32: The Government's Economic Role ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary concept of the government's role in modern society?",
        optionA: "Protecting citizens from internal threats",
        optionB: "Ensuring economic development and welfare",
        optionC: "Implementing laws for social harmony",
        correctAnswer: "B) Ensuring economic development and welfare",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which branch of the government enacts laws and policies for economic development and protection of citizens?",
        optionA: "The Executive",
        optionB: "The Legislature",
        optionC: "The Judiciary",
        correctAnswer: "B) The Legislature",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the government's primary impact on economic development through infrastructure?",
        optionA: "Laying down roads and bridges",
        optionB: "Creating facilities for employment and economic growth",
        optionC: "Regulating the economy through price controls",
        correctAnswer:
          "B) Creating facilities for employment and economic growth",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which type of infrastructure helps people lead a more meaningful life?",
        optionA: "Infrastructure for Employment Generation",
        optionB: "Basic Infrastructure",
        optionC: "Infrastructure for Civic Amenities",
        correctAnswer: "C) Infrastructure for Civic Amenities",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In which sector does the government provide healthcare facilities at an affordable cost?",
        optionA: "Industry",
        optionB: "Education",
        optionC: "Health",
        correctAnswer: "C) Health",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Why does the government involve itself in activities that private companies may not be interested in?",
        optionA: "To compete with private companies",
        optionB: "To earn profits for the government",
        optionC: "To ensure the welfare of people",
        correctAnswer: "C) To ensure the welfare of people",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which government program guarantees a minimum of 100 working days per year to rural workers?",
        optionA: "JRY (Jawahar Rozgar Yojana)",
        optionB: "NREP (National Rural Employment Programme)",
        optionC:
          "MNREGS (Mahatma Gandhi National Rural Employment Guarantee Scheme)",
        correctAnswer:
          "C) MNREGS (Mahatma Gandhi National Rural Employment Guarantee Scheme)",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What has been the impact of the government's efforts on India's GDP and per capita income?",
        optionA: "They have decreased significantly",
        optionB: "They have remained unchanged",
        optionC: "They have gone up significantly",
        correctAnswer: "C) They have gone up significantly",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is one area in which India has earned a great reputation due to government efforts?",
        optionA: "Agriculture",
        optionB: "Industry",
        optionC: "Education",
        correctAnswer: "B) Industry",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the government's primary motive in creating infrastructure and economic development?",
        optionA: "To maximize profits",
        optionB: "To lay the foundation for future private enterprises",
        optionC:
          "To initiate development activities for the benefit of the public",
        correctAnswer:
          "C) To initiate development activities for the benefit of the public",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The concept of the government in modern society is that of a 'Welfare State', which not only protects its citizens from external attacks but also makes available conditions by which their ___________ can take place.",
        options: [
          "cultural development",
          "political development",
          "economic development",
        ],
        answer: "economic development",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Legislature enacts laws and policies to ensure economic development, including laws that guarantee minimum wages to workers and specify the maximum price of common essential commodities like wheat and sugar. These laws prevent economic ___________.",
        options: ["equality", "exploitation", "prosperity"],
        answer: "exploitation",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The government's primary impact on the economic development of the country is through laying down ___________.",
        options: [
          "rules and regulations",
          "infrastructure",
          "taxes and tariffs",
        ],
        answer: "infrastructure",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Basic infrastructure includes facilities like roads, railways, airports, and seaports, which enable people to find employment and improve their economic perspective. It also includes energy-generating facilities to provide ___________.",
        options: ["clean water", "electricity", "healthcare"],
        answer: "electricity",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Infrastructure for Employment Generation involves the establishment of commercial entities such as banks and oil companies, which provide job security to a large number of people. This type of infrastructure promotes ___________.",
        options: ["social welfare", "employment", "education"],
        answer: "employment",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Private companies are known for their professional management and efficiency, often providing services that may outperform government operators. Private companies are primarily motivated by ___________.",
        options: ["profit", "charity", "government subsidies"],
        answer: "profit",
      },
      {
        question:
          "To check migration of rural workers to cities, the government has implemented programs like NREP and MNREGS, in which workers are guaranteed a minimum of 100 working days per year to promote ___________ in rural areas.",
        options: ["industrial development", "self-employment", "urbanization"],
        answer: "self-employment",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The impact of the government's economic presence in India has led to significant improvements, including a reduction in the percentage of people living Below Poverty Line (BPL). Over 25 crore people have been lifted out of poverty in the period from 2011 to 2020, demonstrating ___________.",
        options: [
          "economic challenges",
          "environmental degradation",
          "positive outcomes",
        ],
        answer: "positive outcomes",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The government has played a crucial role in infrastructure development, which has had a great impact on the economic activities of common people. Infrastructure includes facilities such as railways, roads, airports, and dams, as well as providing infrastructure for better quality of life, such as ___________.",
        options: ["schools and colleges", "industrial zones", "luxury resorts"],
        answer: "schools and colleges",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Private companies may not invest in underdeveloped areas, but the government takes steps to develop even the most backward regions. This is because the government's primary motive is to lay infrastructure at a place so that ___________.",
        options: [
          "private companies can profit",
          "development activities can be initiated",
          "government officials can be employed",
        ],
        answer: "development activities can be initiated",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Marginalization is solely based on physical appearance.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Economic, social, and cultural factors are some of the causes of marginalization.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Scheduled Castes (SC) are considered a privileged group.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Scheduled Tribes (ST) are also known as Adivasis.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The government has not provided any reservation for Economically Weaker Sections (EWS) in educational institutions and government employment.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Minority communities are defined solely based on population size.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The police cannot refuse to file an FIR under any circumstances.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The judge in a criminal case decides a case based on personal beliefs.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Social reformers have played no role in eradicating untouchability and discrimination against marginalized classes.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Manual scavenging has been completely eradicated in India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
